<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Последние новости</title>
    <link>http://level3/news/news.php</link>
    <item>
      <title>Jack Dorsey steps down as Twitter CEO</title>
      <link>http://level3/news/news.php?id=5</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey will step down as head of the social media platform he co-founded a decade and a half ago, the company announced on Monday.

Board member and former Chief Technology Officer Parag Agrawal was appointed CEO, effective immediately, and Dorsey will remain a member of the board until his term expires at next year's stockholders' meeting, the company said.

"I've decided to leave Twitter because I believe the company is ready to move on from its founders," Dorsey said in a statement released by Twitter. "My trust in Parag as Twitter's CEO is deep. His work over the past 10 years has been transformational. I'm deeply grateful for his skill, heart, and soul. It's his time to lead."

Dorsey warned of potential pitfalls of a company founder staying on for too long.

"There’s a lot of talk about the importance of a company being 'founder-led,'" Dorsey said. "Ultimately I believe that’s severely limiting and a single point of failure."

He added: "And there aren't many founders that choose their company over their own ego. I know we'll prove this was the right move."

CNBC was the first to report Dorsey’s departure on Monday.

Dorsey remains CEO of Square, his digital payments company. Dorsey is the only person to be CEO of two public companies with market valuations of greater than $5 billion.

In his statement, Dorsey didn’t mention Square or investor pressure previously brought on him to pick one of the executive posts.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 20:41:49 +0300</pubDate>
      <category>Политика</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Joe Biden</title>
      <link>http://level3/news/news.php?id=4</link>
      <description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON — President Joe Biden urged vaccinated Americans to get their Covid booster shots and once again pleaded with those who have yet to be vaccinated to get their first dose in remarks Monday amid growing concerns about the potential threat posed by the new omicron variant.

"The best protection against this new variant or any of the variants out there, the ones we've been dealing with already, is getting fully vaccinated and getting a booster shot," Biden said. "Most Americans are fully vaccinated, but not yet boosted."

While administration officials believe the current vaccines will likely provide protection against the new variant, the U.S. will do everything possible to accelerate the production of new vaccines or boosters if needed, the president said.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 20:33:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <category>Политика</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>«Атлеты должны выступать в той гендерной категории, в которой чувствуют себя лучше». МОК выпутстил свод советов по вопросу трансгендеров в спорте</title>
      <link>http://level3/news/news.php?id=3</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Международный олимпийский комитет (МОК) выпустил свод советов для Международных спортивных федераций по вопросу трансгендеров и спортсменов, которые заявляют противоположную своему полу гендерную идентичность.

В свод вошли 10 принципов, которые, по мнению МОК, должны учитывать Федерации.

МОК считает, что к соревнованиям нужно допускать любых спортсменов, независимо от их пола, статуса или гендерной идентичности. Например, трансгендеров нельзя отстранять от соревнований только из-за того, что они являются трансгендерами.

«Спортсмены должны выступать в той гендерной категории, в которой чувствуют себя лучше», – говорится в советах.

При этом Федерации должны установить критерии, по которым тех или иных спортсменов могут допускать к мужским или женским соревнованиям. Нельзя допускать атлета к выбранной им категории только в том случае, если доказано, что он получит нечестное преимущество или может нанести вред другим спортсменам. Доказательства должны быть вескими, а спортсмен всегда может опротестовать решение Федерации в Спортивном арбитражном суде (CAS).

Также МОК не рекомендует заставлять спортсменов проходить «необязательные медицинские процедуры». Например, сейчас по правилам World Athletics бегуньи на средние дистанции с повышенным уровнем тестостерона должны принимать препараты, снижающие уровень этого гормона.

Еще МОК считает, что для определения допуска спортсмена к выбранной категории нельзя подвергать его гинекологическим и прочим подобным обследованиям, которые направлены на определение его физического пола.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 20:10:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <category>Спорт</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
